MANIVASAGAM SURESH

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

+919566991210

https://manivasagamportfolio.netlify.app/

Bangalore

https://www.linkedin.com/in/manivasagam -s-3534bb157/

https://github.com/ManivasagamSuresh

SKILLS

in

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- HTML
- CSS
- · React.Js
- Next.Js
- Node.Js
- MongoDB
- TailwindCss
- Bootstrap
- Sass

EDUCATION

BE-Automobile

PSG college of Technology, Coimbatore 2016-2020

CERTIFICATE

MERN - Full Stack Developer program

GUVI Geeks Network Pvt. Ltd

PROFILE

A self-motivated, adaptable developer known for high productivity and efficient task completion. Possess specialized skills in JavaScript, React, Next.Js, Node.Js and MongoDB. Excel at problem solving, collaboration, and adaptability, ensuring seamless team integration and project success.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FRONT-END ENGINEER

AYOO Care

Nov 2023 - Current

- Developed patient and admin websites using modern front-end technologies:
 - Admin website: Built with React.js and styled with Bootstrap, featuring interactive dashboards, data visualization, and PDF management for efficient administration.
 - Patient website: Built with Next.js and styled with Sass, providing features for appointment booking and viewing, improving user interaction with AYOO Care's healthcare services.
- Implemented key features across platforms:
 - Admin website: Enabled creating, rescheduling, and viewing appointments, requesting and uploading documents, viewing PDFs, and generating statistical graphs for insights.
 - Patient website: Focused on enabling users to book and view appointments.
- Contributed to product documentation for four platforms (two websites and two mobile apps), ensuring clarity and consistency.
- Actively participated in manual testing during app releases, identifying and fixing bugs to ensure a smooth user experience.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to build a seamless virtual and in-person healthcare experience, integrating technology into AYOO Care's patient-centric approach.

INTERN SOFTWARE ENGINEER

TBD-HEALTH

May 2023 - June 2023

 As an Intern Software Engineer, I developed features in UI/front-end for the product website using React.Js and backend for partner services with Next.Js and AWS DynamoDB.

FULL STACK PROJECTS

FOOD E-COMMERCE WEBSITE

https://kaviseyon-foods.vercel.app/

- · Users can sign-up and sign-in with email, but can also place orders without logging in.
- Allows users to view products, add them to the cart, and place orders using Razorpay payment gateway.
- Users can track their orders through the order summary, where order status and tracking links are updated by the admin.
- Admins can view all products and orders, and have the ability to update order statuses and provide tracking information.
- Technologies and libraries used: Next.js, Tailwind, Redux Toolkit, MongoDB, Razorpay, Nodemailer

FASHION E-COMMERCE WEBSITE

https://grand-quokka-39f552.netlify.app

- Users can Sign-up, Sign-in with Email id.
- Allows users to view, wishlist, move products to cart and buy the products with help of Razor pay
 payment gateway.
- Technologies and libraries used: React.Js, Node.Js, MongoDB, JSON web token, Redux-Toolkit, Razor pay, Bootstrap

VIDEO SHARING - SOCIAL MEDIA PLATFORM

https://cheerful-valkyrie-754245.netlify.app

- Users can Sign-up, Sign-in with Email id.
- Allows users to view, like, dislike, add comments to the video, subscribe a channel, and post a video.
- Technologies and libraries used: React.Js, Node.Js, MongoDB, tailwind CSS, JSON web token, Redux-Toolkit, socket.io

CHAT-APP

https://capable-gelato-a223ec.netlify.app

- Users can Login with their G-mail, create a chat box, receive and send messages in the chat box.
- Technologies and libraries used: React.Js, Node.Js, MongoDB, Pusher, Firebase

TOURNAMENT SYSTEM APP

https://steady-shortbread-751776.netlify.app

- Users can Login and join their favorite tournament, cancel and edit their registration.
- Admin can create, edit and delete the tournaments.
- Technologies and libraries used: React.Js, Node.Js, MongoDB, tailwind CSS, Redux-Toolkit